Finding Aid for Daughters of the American Revolution. Ypsilanti Chapter (Ypsilanti, Mich.) records, 1896-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Daughters of the American Revolution. Ypsilanti Chapter (Ypsilanti, Mich.) records 1896-1985
Daughters of the American Revolution. Ypsilanti Chapter (Ypsilanti, Mich.).
1.5 linear feet and 1 oversize folder
85131 Be.1 2; Be.1 Outsize
Ypsilanti chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution; organizational records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the chapter (donor no. 6008 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The first regular meeting of the Ypsilanti chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution was held October 19, 1896.
The record group includes secretary's minutes, treasurer's books, by-laws, and annual reports. In addition, there is a minute book of the organization's Junior Committee, 1948-1952. Of genealogical value is the compilation made of the names of individuals buried in the Oakwood Cemetery, Saline, Michigan.
Subjects:
Cemeteries--Michigan--Saline.; Daughters of the American Revolution. Ypsilanti Chapter (Ypsilanti, Mich.).; Patriotic societies--Michigan--Ypsilanti.; Oakwood Cemetery (Saline, Mich.).; Women--Michigan--Ypsilanti--Societies and clubs.; Ypsilanti (Mich.).
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Cemeteries--Michigan--Saline.; Oakwood Cemetery (Saline, Mich.); Cemeteries--Michigan--Saline; Tombs and sepulchral monuments.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Secretary's minutes, 1896-1985
  - 1896-1902 (Box 1)
  - 1902-1907 (Box 1)
  - 1907-1914 (Box 1)
  - 1914-1921 (Box 1)
  - 1921-1924 (Box 1)
  - 1924-1929 (Box 1)
  - 1929-1932 (Box 1)
  - 1932-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1951 (Box 1)
  - 1951-1962 (Box 1)
  - 1962-1968 (Box 1)
  - 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - 1974-1985, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Treasurer's books, 1896-1970
  - 1896-1918 (Box 2)
  - 1918-1927 (Box 2)
  - 1927-1936 (Box 2)
  - 1936-1954 (Box 2)
  - 1954-1970 (Box 2)
- Other records
  - By-laws (Box 2)
  - Annual reports, 1974/1975-1984/1985 (Box 2)
  - Junior Committee: Secretary-Treasurer's book, 1946-1952 (Box 2)
  - Compilation of burials in Oakwood Cemetery, Saline, Michigan, 1958 (Box 2)
    (include photographs)
  - Diagrams of Oakwood Cemetery, 6 items (Folder Be.1)